<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Demos on Pivotal Workshop</title>
    <link>/demos/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Demos on Pivotal Workshop</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    
	<atom:link href="/demos/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/intro-creds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/intro-creds/</guid>
      <description> Introduction &amp;amp; Credentials In today&amp;rsquo;s workshop you will get hands on experience creating a templated app in Visual Studio, reviewing the cloud foundry manifest, pushing the app to Pivotal Application Services, attaching an auto-scaler to the app, and trying out different routes.
Your workshop proctor should have provided URL&amp;rsquo;s and credentials prior to beginning the labs. Please have this information handy for the next lab.
You will need:  API URL of your workshop Pivotal Cloud Foundry (PCF) foundation URL of App Manager User name and password to login to the foundation Org and Space associated with the user account  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/setup-environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/setup-environment/</guid>
      <description>Setup Desktop Environment Goal The labs in this workshop make use of Powershell, the Cloud Foundry cli (cf cli), and local environment variables. The following steps will confirm you have the correct configuration.
Prerequisites  Visual Studio (min 2015) Web Browser (Chrome, Firefox, Edge, Safari)(Not Internet Explorer) Powershell Internet connection  Download and Validate cf cli  Download the cli.
 Unpack the zip file.
 Double click cf-installer.exe to begin installation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/create-microservice-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/create-microservice-win/</guid>
      <description>Create a .NET Core Microservice for Windows Goal Using the installed Visual Studio templates, create a new app based on Steeltoe that is ready for Cloud Foundry Windows Diego cell.
Prerequisites  Visual Studio (min 2015) Internet Access  Load the Steeltoe Template for Cloud Foundry  From the Visual Studio homepage, choose File then New then Project. This will bring up the &amp;ldquo;New Project&amp;rdquo; window.
 Choose Installed in the left panel and locate the search box at the top right.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/explore-appmanager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/explore-appmanager/</guid>
      <description>Explore Applications Manager Goal Now that you&amp;rsquo;ve pushed an app, log in to App Manager and explore the many options available.
Prerequisites  Internet Access Web Browser (Chrome, Firefox, Edge, Safari)(Not Internet Explorer)  Log in to App Manager  Open PAS Apps Manager web site provided in the Introduction slide.  Log in with the student account creds assigned workshop proctor..
 Once logged in, notice your Org and Space is automatically loaded.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/attach-autoscaler/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/attach-autoscaler/</guid>
      <description>Setup Auto-scaling Goal From the home page of your app, in App Manager, attach an autoscaler service to it with scaling rules.
Prerequisites  Pushed app Internet Access Web Browser (Chrome, Firefox, Edge, Safari)(Not Internet Explorer)  Find the autoscaler service and bind to a space  Open the &amp;ldquo;Markeplace&amp;rdquo; of services within App Manager.
 Locate the &amp;ldquo;App Autoscaler&amp;rdquo; service and click on it. This will show you the &amp;ldquo;plans&amp;rdquo; associated with that service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/add-route/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/add-route/</guid>
      <description>Add a New Route Goal From the home page of your app, in App Manager, add a second route to the app.
Prerequisites  Pushed app Internet Access Web Browser (Chrome, Firefox, Edge, Safari)(Not Internet Explorer)  Add a new a route to your app  From the home page of your app, choose the &amp;ldquo;Route&amp;rdquo; tab. Notice there is one route attached to your app. It was created from the Host value in the app&amp;rsquo;s manifest.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/pasw-to-steeltoe-basics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/pasw-to-steeltoe-basics/</guid>
      <description>Next Steps Congratulations you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the PASW Workshop!
Now that you are a cf push expert, it&amp;rsquo;s time to get in to some more advanced topics. Continue to learn and experience more about cloud-native best practices with the Steeltoe Framework. The following labs will get you hands-on deploying .NET microservices.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve run out of time and need to take a break, don&amp;rsquo;t forget all the other ways to lean about Pivotal and the Steeltoe Framework.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/env-vars-win/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/env-vars-win/</guid>
      <description>Cloud Native - Environment Variables Goal Environment variables are a staple of cloud native best practices, but if you&amp;rsquo;ve been developing on a Windows desktop you may not be that familiar. This lab aims to introduce how a cloud native .NET app should hold very little configuration within, and instead rely on it&amp;rsquo;s configuration to be provided in environment variables.
Prerequisites  Visual Studio (min 2015) Internet Access Web Browser (Chrome, Firefox, Edge, Safari)(Not Internet Explorer) Powershell  Create a new Visual Studio Steeltoe project  From the Visual Studio homepage, choose File &amp;gt; New &amp;gt; Project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/cups/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/cups/</guid>
      <description>User Provided Services with Steeltoe Goal Environment variables are a very powerful feature of cloud native applications but sometimes we need all the apps in a given space (or environment) to share settings. User provided services are a great way to accomplish this. In this lab we will create a service that is available to all apps in a given space via environment variables.
Note, this lab assumes you already have the Steeltoe template app opened in Visual Studio and you have already logged in to a foundation with the cf cli.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/actuators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/actuators/</guid>
      <description>Include Steeltoe Actuators and Create a Custom Health Check Goal Assuming you have already pushed an app based on the Steeltoe Cloud Foundry templates, this lab will review what additions were made in the project to enable Actuators and the automatic benefits in App Manager.
Prerequisites  Visual Studio (min 2015) Internet Access Web Browser (Chrome, Firefox, Edge, Safari)(Not Internet Explorer)  Add Steeltoe Management Actuators to the app  Open the Startup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/using-actuators/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/using-actuators/</guid>
      <description>App Manager with Management Actuators Goal Now that you have pushed an app to the foundation that implments Steeltoe Actuators, lets explore how App Manager makes that data available for debugging and analysis.
Prerequisites  Internet Access Web Browser (Chrome, Firefox, Edge, Safari)(Not Internet Explorer)  Discover how App Manager works with each actuator endpoint  Open the App Manager website in a browser.
 Navigate to your app&amp;rsquo;s home page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/logging/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/logging/</guid>
      <description>Steeltoe Dynamic Logging Goal Assuming you have already pushed an app based on the Steeltoe Cloud Foundry templates, this lab will review what additions were made in the project to enable dynamic logging and the automatic benefits in App Manager.
Prerequisites  Visual Studio (min 2015) Internet Access Web Browser (Chrome, Firefox, Edge, Safari)(Not Internet Explorer)  Enable Steeltoe dynamic logging  There are additional features that came pre-configured in the Steeltoe template app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/steeltoe-basics-to-steeltoe-aszure-storage/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/steeltoe-basics-to-steeltoe-aszure-storage/</guid>
      <description>Next Steps Congratulations you&amp;rsquo;ve completed the Steeltoe basics Workshop!
Continue to learn and experience more about cloud-native best practices by using the Azure SQL broker with Steeltoe Framework. The following labs will get you hands-on..
If you&amp;rsquo;ve run out of time and need to take a break, don&amp;rsquo;t forget all the other ways to lean about Pivotal and the Steeltoe Framework.
  Pivotal Education Services Self Guided Learning Pivotal Workshops     The Platform Acceleration Lab (PAL) is an immersive, best practices set of courses that enables developers and architects to develop new applications, move applications (replatforming), and modernize existing applications on Pivotal Cloud Foundry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/bind-sb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/bind-sb/</guid>
      <description>Bind the Microsoft Azure Service Broker Goal Locate the Azure SQL in the Marketplace and make an instance of it available for binding in your space.
Prerequisites  Internet Access Web Browser (Chrome, Firefox, Edge, Safari)(Not Internet Explorer)  Bind the Azure SQL service to your space  Open the App Manager website in a browser.
 Navigate to the &amp;ldquo;Marketplace&amp;rdquo; in the left navigation.
 Local the &amp;ldquo;Azure SQL Database Service&amp;rdquo; and click.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/dbcontext/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/dbcontext/</guid>
      <description>Consume the Microsoft Azure Service Broker in your application Goal With the Azure SQL service available for binding, create the necessary DBContext and list the newly created tables&amp;rsquo; content.
Prerequisites  Visual Studio (min 2015) Internet Access  Bind the SQL service to your application  Back in Visual Studio, open the manifest.yml file by double clicking and add the following to the services section (create that section if it&amp;rsquo;s not there).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/push-microservice/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/push-microservice/</guid>
      <description>Push the Microservice to Pivotal Application Services Platform Goal Using Visual Studio, compile the app to create an artifact. Then push the artifact to the Platform, for deployment.
Prerequisites  Visual Studio (min 2015) PAS API Access PAS App Manager Access  Create the App Artifact  With the Steeltoe Microservice app opened in Visual Studio, right click on the project name and choose publish. (No need to build or restore, it will happen automatically)  The &amp;ldquo;Publish&amp;rdquo; window will open where you can choose the FolderProfile.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/demos/next-steps/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/demos/next-steps/</guid>
      <description>Continuing Your .NET Cloud Native Journey Congratulations you&amp;rsquo;ve completed Steeltoe Azure Storage Workshop!
Continue to learn and experience more about cloud native best practices, with Pivotal.
  Pivotal Education Services Self Guided Learning Pivotal Workshops     The Platform Acceleration Lab (PAL) is an immersive, best practices set of courses that enables developers and architects to develop new applications, move applications (replatforming), and modernize existing applications on Pivotal Cloud Foundry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>